<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../recipe.xsl"?>
<!-- Include entities to be used in the xml -->
<!DOCTYPE invoice [
	<!ENTITY section SYSTEM "section.xml">
	<!ENTITY % externalEntities SYSTEM "/entities.dtd">
	%externalEntities;
]>

<Recipe title="Cheap Soft Toffee" yields="about 100 1-inch squares">
	<Source>A VanOrman Original</Source>
	<Section>&section;</Section>
	<LastModified year=" 2025"
		month=" 3"
		day=" 21" />

	<Description id="Description">
		When Ransom was growing up, his family used to visit Canada every few years.
		One of Ransom's favorite treats up there was " MacIntosh's Creamy Toffee".
		Ransom tried many recipes to duplicate it and came up with a really good one.
		However, it requires some ingredients that we rarely have on hand.
		So, this recipe is not quite as good, and you have to be a bit more careful, but it is good.
	</Description>

	<Ingredients id="Ingredients">
		<section>
			<ingredient name="Brown Sugar" amount="&frac12; Cup" />
			<ingredient name="Corn Syrup" amount="&frac12; Cup" />
			<ingredient name="Sugar" amount="1 Cup" />
			<ingredient name="Evaporated Milk" amount="1 Can" />
			<ingredient name="Butter"
				amount="&frac12; Cup"
				amountNote="1 stick" />
			<ingredient name="Vanilla" amount="1 teaspoon" />
		</section>
	</Ingredients>

	<Instructions id="Instructions">
		<section>
			<instruction>Lightly spray a 9&inch; &by; 13&inch; pan with non-stick spray.</instruction>
			<instruction>In a large, non-stick pot, combine all ingredients except Vanilla.</instruction>
			<instruction>Heat mixture on medium, using a candy thermometer to monitor temperature.</instruction>
			<instruction>Stirring very frequently, heat to 253&deg; F. <span class="NOTE">(This will take half an hour or so.)</span><br /><span class="NOTE">(I know 253&deg; sounds weird, but 250&deg; leaves it runny, and 255&deg; makes it brittle.)</span></instruction>
			<instruction>When it reaches temperature, immediately remove the pot from the heat.</instruction>
			<instruction>Stir in Vanilla.</instruction>
			<instruction>Pour mixture onto the prepared pan and spread evenly.</instruction>
			<instruction>Let the mixture cool completely.</instruction>
		</section>
	</Instructions>

	<Notes id="Notes">
		<note><span class="SUPER_EMPHASIZE">Warning!</span> Mixture will more than double while heating, then will reduce as it nears the correct temperature.</note>
		<note>Although the original recipe is cooked on high, this one is intentionally cooked on medium. If you cook it higher, small flecks begin to form which makes it look bad.</note>
		<note>Cutting it up is a challenge. I used a hot, large, sharp chopping knife, and was able to get it if I was patient.<br />Alternatively, you can cut it when it is <span class="NOTE">mostly</span> cool, but you need to place the cut pieces around so they don' t touch. </note>
	</Notes>

	<Modifications id="Modifications">
		<modification>About a minute after pouring the mixture into the prepared pan, sprinkle it with about 1 Cup Chocolate Chips. Let sit for another 2 minutes, then spread the now softened Chocolate Chips with a spatula. Then let cool normally.</modification>
	</Modifications>
</Recipe>
