<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../recipe.xsl"?>
<!-- Include entities to be used in the xml -->
<!DOCTYPE invoice [
	<!ENTITY section SYSTEM "section.xml">
	<!ENTITY % externalEntities SYSTEM "/entities.dtd">
	%externalEntities;
]>

<Recipe title="Biscuits" yields="about 12">
	<Source>From an old cookbook</Source>

	<Section>&section;</Section>
	<LastModified year="2025"
		month="4"
		day="1" />

	<Description id="Description">
		These days, the easiest way to do biscuits is to buy a tube of them at the grocery story, pop them open and bake them.
		However, if you want good biscuits, that just won't do.
		This recipe is nothing special, but it does produce biscuits that are far superior to the junk you get out of a tube.
	</Description>

	<Ingredients id="Ingredients">
		<section>
			<ingredient name="Flour" amount="1&frac34; Cups" />
			<ingredient name="Salt" amount="&frac12; teaspoon" />
			<ingredient name="Baking Powder" amount="1 Tablespoon" />
			<ingredient name="Butter"
				nameNote="COLD!"
				amount="6 Tablespoons" />
			<ingredient name="Milk" amount="&frac34; Cup" />
		</section>
	</Ingredients>

	<Instructions id="Instructions">
		<section>
			<instruction>Preheat oven to 400&deg;.</instruction>
			<instruction>In a bowl, combine Flour, Salt and Baking Powder.</instruction>
			<instruction>Slice the butter into 1 Tablespoon slices and use a pastry blender to cut butter into flour until combination is consistency of coarse cornmeal.</instruction>
			<instruction>Add milk all at once and stir until dough doesn't stick to sides of bowl. <span class="NOTE">(Less than 1 minute.)</span></instruction>
			<instruction>Dust the countertop with flour and roll out the dough until it is it is about &frac12;" thick.</instruction>
			<instruction>Fold in half, then in half again.</instruction>
			<instruction>Repeat Steps 5 and 6 at least four times.</instruction>
			<instruction>The final time, roll out dough 1" thick.</instruction>
			<instruction>Cut out biscuits with a round cookie cutter approximately 2&frac12;" in diameter.</instruction>
			<instruction>Place on greased cookie sheet.</instruction>
			<instruction>Bake at 400&deg; for 12-15 minutes, until just turning golden brown.</instruction>
		</section>
	</Instructions>

	<Notes id="Notes">
		<note>A Pastry Blender is not an electrical appliance! It is a hand-held tool with a bunch of blades used to gently mix doughs of this sort. If you cannot find a pastry blender, use a fork.<br /><img src="PastryBlender.png" style="margin-left:5em;" /></note>
		<note>If you do not have a round cookie cutter, use a cup or glass.</note>
	</Notes>

	<Modifications id="Modifications">
		<modification>To make the tops a little more tender, gently brush the tops with milk or butter just before baking.</modification>
		<modification>If you want to have larger Biscuits for something like Biscuits &amp; Gravy, just use a larger cutter in step 9, but it will yield fewer Biscuits.</modification>
	</Modifications>
</Recipe>
