<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../recipe.xsl"?>
<!-- Include entities to be used in the xml -->
<!DOCTYPE invoice [
	<!ENTITY section SYSTEM "section.xml">
	<!ENTITY % externalEntities SYSTEM "/entities.dtd">
	%externalEntities;
]>

<Recipe title="Banana Boats" yields="1">
	<Section>&section;</Section>
	<LastModified year="2025"
		month="4"
		day="30" />

	<Description id="Description"> When camping, you almost always have a campfire at night. And what is better than having a treat just before bedtime? <br />This is a recipe that leverages the coles from a campfire. </Description>

	<Ingredients id="Ingredients">
		<section id="IngredientsBananaBoat">
			<ingredient name="Banana" nameNote="Not Peeled" amount="1" />
			<ingredient name="Miniture Marshmallows" amount="1-2 Tablespoons" />
			<ingredient name="Chocolate Chips" amount="1-2 Tablespoons" />
		</section>
	</Ingredients>

	<Instructions id="Instructions">
		<section id="Instructions">
			<instruction>Build a campfire that will have lots of coles.</instruction>
			<instruction>Hold the Banana flat and slice it half way deep, from end to end, making sure to not cut through bottom peel.<img src="SlicingBanana.png" style="width:10em; vertical-align:text-top;" /></instruction>
			<instruction>Position the Banana in the middle of a sheet of tin foil that is big enough to wrap all the way around the Banana. <span class="NOTE">(about 12&inches; &by; 18&inches;)</span></instruction>
			<instruction>Gently open the slice on the Banana and fill it with a mixture of the Miniture Marshmallows and Chocolate Chips.</instruction>
			<instruction>Wrap the tin foil around the Banana, making sure that none of it is exposed at all.</instruction>
			<instruction>When the campfire coles are ready, place the Banana Boat half-way deep in them, positioned with the fillings on the top.</instruction>
			<instruction>Wait until the Miniture Marshmallows and Chocolate Chips have melted. <span class="NOTE">(about 5-10 minutes)</span></instruction>
			<instruction>Carefully <span class="NOTE">(so you don't get burned)</span> remove the Banana Boat from the campfire coles, and gently open the foil so the contents are fully exposed.</instruction>
			<instruction>Dig in with a spoon! </instruction>
		</section>
	</Instructions>

	<Notes>
		<note>The Ingredient amounts are for a single Banana Boat. But you'll definately want to do more, so just get enough Bananas for everybody, and whole bags of toppings.&smiley;</note>
	</Notes>

	<Modifications id="Modifications">
		<modification>Add other ingredients, such as: <ul>
				<li>Spices such as Sugar and Cinnamon</li>
				<li>Fruit such as Strawberries, Raspberries, etc.</li>
				<li>Candy, such as M<span style="font-size:.75em;">&amp;</span>Ms, broken up Peanut Butter Cups, pieces of Twix, etc.</li>
				<li>Graham Cracker pieces</li>
				<li>Cold Cereal such as Cinnamon Toast Crunch, etc.</li>
				<li>Nuts <span class="NOTE">(sliced or crushed)</span></li>
			</ul>
		</modification>

	</Modifications>
</Recipe>
