<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../recipe.xsl"?>
<!-- Include entities to be used in the xml -->
<!DOCTYPE invoice [
	<!ENTITY section SYSTEM "section.xml">
	<!ENTITY % externalEntities SYSTEM "/entities.dtd">
	%externalEntities;
]>

<Recipe title="3rd Degree Buffalo Wings" yields="5 servings">
	<Source>A VanOrman Original</Source>

	<Section>&section;</Section>
	<LastModified year="2025"
		month="3"
		day="31" />

	<Description id="Description"> When Ransom made his first attempt at this recipe, he left the room while the oil heated <span class="NOTE">(with the lid on)</span>. When he came back, the oil was smoking, so he lifted the lid to let it cool. <br /> Long story short, it burst into flames, splashed on his hand, arm and foot causing 1st, 2nd and near 3rd degree burns. <span class="NOTE">(The docs all said it was 3rd degree, but it healed without surgery, so they changed their mind.)</span> And it melted the microwave oven above the stove, totally destroying it. <br /> With Joshua's help, they got the lid back on the pan, then used baking soda to put out the rest of the fire shortly before the firemen showed up.<br />Only a few days later, with his foot and arm bandaged up, Ransom managed to finish cooking these and they turned out great! </Description>

	<Ingredients id="Ingredients">
		<section id="IngredientsWings" title="Wings">
			<ingredient name="All-Purpose Flour" amount="1 Cup" />
			<ingredient name="Paprika" amount="&frac12; teaspoon" />
			<ingredient name="Cayenne Pepper" amount="&frac12; teaspoon" />
			<ingredient name="Salt" amount="&frac12; teaspoon" />
			<ingredient name="Chicken Wings"
				amount="20 Pieces"
				amountNote="About 3 lbs." />
			<ingredient name="Oil" amountNote="for Deep Frying" />
		</section>
		<section id="IngredientsSauce" title="Sauce">
			<ingredient name="Butter" amount="&frac12; Cup" />
			<ingredient name="Hot Sauce"
				nameNote="Such as Tapat&#xED;o"
				amount="&frac12; Cup" />
			<ingredient name="Ground Black Pepper" amount="2 Dashes" />
			<ingredient name="Garlic Powder" amount="2 Dashes" />
		</section>
	</Ingredients>

	<Instructions id="Instructions">
		<section id="InstructionsWings" title="Wings">
			<instruction>In a large bowl mix together the Flour, Paprika, Cayenne Pepper and Salt.</instruction>
			<instruction>Place Chicken Wings in mixture and stir until they are well coated.</instruction>
			<instruction>Cover bowl and refrigerate for 60 to 90 minutes.<br /><span class="Note">(While waiting, make sauce)</span></instruction>
			<instruction>Heat Oil in a deep fryer to 375&deg;</instruction>
			<instruction>Fry Chicken Wings in hot oil for 10 to 15 minutes, until they begin to turn brown.</instruction>
			<instruction>Place cooked Chicken Wings into a large bowl or pan.</instruction>
			<instruction>Coat Chicken Wings with sauce and stir until covered.</instruction>
		</section>
		<section id="InstructionsSauce" title="Sauce">
			<instruction>In a small saucepan, combine Butter, Hot Sauce, Pepper and Garlic Powder.</instruction>
			<instruction>Over low heat, stir together until Butter is melted and mixture is well blended.</instruction>
			<instruction>Remove from heat and let stand until Wings are done cooking.</instruction>
		</section>
	</Instructions>

	<Modifications id="Modifications">
		<modification>
			Thise original recipe had you use a frying pan instead of a deep fryer.
			If you read the description, you can understand why this was changed. &smiley;
			However, you can use a frying pan on medium high if you are more careful and don't leave the kitchen while waiting for it to heat up.
		</modification>
	</Modifications>
</Recipe>
