<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../recipe.xsl"?>
<!-- Include entities to be used in the xml -->
<!DOCTYPE invoice [
	<!ENTITY section SYSTEM "section.xml">
	<!ENTITY % externalEntities SYSTEM "/entities.dtd">
	%externalEntities;
]>

<Recipe title="Dutch Spanish Rice" yields="10-12 Servings">
	<Source />

	<Section>&section;</Section>
	<LastModified year="2025"
		month="5"
		day="4" />

	<Description id="Description"> Ransom's dad, Grandpa John, originally cooked a version of this recipe over a camp fire in a Dutch Oven. He would cook it with plenty of hamburger and homemade bottled tomatoes and serve it as a main course. <br /> This recipe is a little simpler and is intended as a side-dish. </Description>

	<Ingredients id="Ingredients">
		<section>
			<ingredient name="Onions"
				nameNote="Medium"
				amount="2"
				amountNote="or 1 Large" />
			<ingredient name="Hamburger" amount="1 lb." />
			<ingredient name="Rice" amount="3 Cups" />
			<ingredient name="Diced Tomatoes" amount="2 14.5-oz. Cans" />
			<ingredient name="Tomato Sauce" amount="2 15-oz. Cans" />
			<ingredient name="Salt" amount="1 Tablespoon" />
			<ingredient name="Pepper" amount="1 teaspoon" />
			<ingredient name="Water" amount="1 Quart" />
			<ingredient name="Green Bell Pepper" amount="1" />
		</section>
	</Ingredients>

	<Instructions id="Instructions">
		<section>
			<instruction>Chop Onions into small pieces. <span class="NOTE">(about &frac12;&inch; &by; 1&inch;)</span></instruction>
			<instruction>In a large pot, combine Onions and Hamburger, and cook on high until hamburger is browned.</instruction>
			<instruction>Add Rice, Tomatoes, Tomato Sauce, Salt, Pepper and Water, then mix well.</instruction>
			<instruction>Put a lid on the pot and stirring frequently with a Spatula, heat mixture until it starts to boil.</instruction>
			<instruction>While mixture is heating, cut Peppers into small pieces <span class="NOTE">(about &frac12;&inch; &by; 1&inch;)</span>, then stir them into the mixture.</instruction>
			<instruction>Once mixture starts to boil, reduce heat to medium.</instruction>
			<instruction>Stirring occasionally, let simmer until rice is cooked. <span class="NOTE">(About 30-45 minutes.)</span></instruction>
		</section>
	</Instructions>

	<Notes id="Notes">
		<note><span class="EMPHASIZE">It is <span class="SUPER_EMPHASIZE">crucial</span> to scrape the bottom well when stirring!</span><br />Otherwise, everything will end up tasting burned.</note>
	</Notes>

	<Modifications id="Modifications">
		<modification>Add an extra pound or two of Hamburger to turn this into a main course instead of a side dish. <span class="NOTE"><span class="HIGHLIGHT">NOTE</span>: Main course servings are about double side-dish servings, so it will serve only 5-6 people.</span></modification>
		<modification>If you wish larger chunks of Tomato, you can use cans of Sliced or even Stewed Tomatoes.<br />If you do so, you may wish to use your Spatula to break up the bigger pieces.</modification>
		<modification>For a little savorier taste, use 2 Poblano peppers instead of the Green Bell Pepper.<br />If you do this, add them when adding the Onions instead of later on.</modification>
	</Modifications>
</Recipe>
