<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../recipe.xsl"?>
<!-- Include entities to be used in the xml -->
<!DOCTYPE invoice [
	<!ENTITY section SYSTEM "section.txt">
	<!ENTITY % externalEntities SYSTEM "/entities.dtd">
	%externalEntities;
]>

<Recipe title="Easy Gravy" yields="2 Cups">
	<Source>Basic</Source>

	<Section>&section;</Section>
	<LastModified year="2025"
		month="3"
		day="31" />

	<Description id="Description">
		There are many ways to make gravy.
		Some take hours and tons of ingredients.
		This recipe is the simplest we have found and is pretty much the only one Ransom uses.
	</Description>

	<Ingredients id="Ingredients">
		<section>
			<ingredient name="Broth"
				nameNote="Double-Strength"
				amount="2 Cups" />
			<ingredient name="Water"
				nameNote="Cold"
				amount="&frac14; Cup" />
			<ingredient name="Corn Starch" amount="2 Tablespoons" />
		</section>
	</Ingredients>

	<Instructions id="Instructions">
		<section>
			<instruction>Pour Broth into a small saucepan and begin to bring to a boil.</instruction>
			<instruction>In the meantime, combine Cold Water and Corn Starch in a small cup and mix until there are <span class="EMPHASIZE">absolutely no lumps</span> at all.</instruction>
			<instruction>When Broth begins to boil, slowly pour in Cold Water/Corn Starch mix while stirring constantly.</instruction>
			<instruction>Let entire mixture come to a boil, while stirring constantly.</instruction>
			<instruction>Remove from heat, and it is ready to serve.</instruction>
		</section>
	</Instructions>

	<Notes id="Notes">
		<note>Broth can be any flavor you want: Beef, Chicken, Onion, Vegetable, etc. <br /><span class="NOTE">(The only flavor we don't recommend is Pork.)</span></note>
		<note><span class="EMPHASIZE">Always use <span class="SUPER_EMPHASIZE">Cold</span> Water!</span><br />Corn Starch will mix readily with Cold Water. However, if you use hot, or even warm water, it tends to clump <span class="HIGHLIGHT">terribly</span>.</note>
	</Notes>

	<Modifications id="Modifications">
		<modification>You can create the Double-Strength Beef Broth by using 2 Cups of Water + 4 Bouillon Cubes <span class="NOTE">(or the equivalent)</span>.</modification>
		<modification>Instead of Double-Strength Broth, you can use dripping from a roast, chicken, etc. My favorite is to use the drippings from a turkey. <span class="NOTE">(You just have to make sure you have enough liquid.)</span></modification>
		<modification>If you like your gravy thicker, you can use more Corn Starch, or if you like it thinner you can use less. <span class="NOTE">(Ransom once used so much the gravy could be sliced. &smiley;)</span></modification>
		<modification>You can replace the Corn Starch with Flour but use <span class="HIGHLIGHT">Warm</span> Water. <!-- TODO QZX: Check measurement of Flour --> However, even though it tastes fine, it changes the color of the gravy so that it is much lighter and more opaque.</modification>
	</Modifications>
</Recipe>
