<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../recipe.xsl"?>
<!-- Include entities to be used in the xml -->
<!DOCTYPE invoice [
	<!ENTITY section SYSTEM "section.xml">
	<!ENTITY % externalEntities SYSTEM "/entities.dtd">
	%externalEntities;
]>

<Recipe title="Queso Hondo" yields="2 cups">
	<Source>From the kitchen of a random friend at a party</Source>

	<Section>&section;</Section>
	<LastModified year="2025"
		month="3"
		day="31" />

	<Description id="Description"> We have purchased all sorts of dips, such as nacho cheese, for corn chips, but nothing really had that <span class="HIGHLIGHT">wow</span> we wanted. Then, at a party, we tried a dip that really impressed us. We asked around and found out it was "homemade" and we coaxed the recipe out of them. <br /> First, you need to know that in Spanish, the letter "i" is pronounced "ee". While eating in a Mexican restaurant, Ransom and Jennie were served a tasty cheese dip. Ransom learned Spanish on his mission, but didn't know the word for "dip", so, in Spanish, he asked the waiter who replied "hondo". Ransom thought that a little odd, but later realized that when he said "dip" he said it with a Spanish accent, so the waiter thought he said "deep". The word for "cheese" is "queso" (pronounced "KAY-so"), so ever since, we have called this dish Queso Hondo. </Description>
	<Ingredients id="Ingredients">
		<section>
			<ingredient name="Processed Cheese Spread"
				nameNote="Such as Velveeta"
				amount="1 Cup" />
			<ingredient name="Salsa" amount="1 Cup" />
		</section>
	</Ingredients>

	<Instructions id="Instructions">
		<section>
			<instruction>Cut Cheese Spread into, &frac12;-inch cubes</instruction>
			<instruction>Heat the Cheese in the microwave oven for 30 seconds.</instruction>
			<instruction>Stir the Cheese.</instruction>
			<instruction>Repeat steps 2 and 3 until the Cheese is melted.</instruction>
			<instruction>Add Salsa and mix.</instruction>
			<instruction>Heat in microwave oven for 30 seconds.</instruction>
			<instruction>Stir the mixture.</instruction>
			<instruction>Repeat steps 6 and 7 until mixture is smooth.</instruction>
		</section>
	</Instructions>

	<Notes id="Notes">
		<note>Do not use Plain Cheese, such as Cheddar. It turns into a glob instead of a spread.</note>
		<note>Do not use Nacho Cheese. It turns into a soup instead of a spread.</note>
		<note>Chunky salsa is usually more appealing.</note>
		<note>You can use Mild, Medium, or Hot Salsa, depending on your preference.</note>
	</Notes>

</Recipe>
